<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: apps | B-Spoked]]></title>
  <link href="http://b-spoked.com/blog/categories/apps/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://b-spoked.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-14T20:54:03+12:00</updated>
  <id>http://b-spoked.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[B-Spoked]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[JQuery Mobile App Development]]></title>
    <link href="http://b-spoked.com/blog/2012/08/11/jquery-mobile-app-development/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-11T13:18:00+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://b-spoked.com/blog/2012/08/11/jquery-mobile-app-development</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been using <a href="http://jquerymobile.com" target="_blank">JQuery Mobile</a> for about a year now so I thought I would write up my thoughts on it.
I also will include some usefull add-ins I have used in conjunction to JQuery Mobile in my development travels.</p>




<!-- more -->


<h2>Reasons to go there</h2>


<p><strong>Prototypes:</strong> Great for quick prototypes.</p>


<p>Becuase it is so quick to get started with a JQuery Mobile project I will often use it to create quick prototypes around a concept I am working on.
While the final product may end out being created with a different technology if you need to quickly get something running to help visualise an idea then
JQuery Mobile will definatly be your friend.</p>




<p><strong>Ease of learning:</strong> Easy to get started and understand.</p>


<p>As long as you know a bit of simple html and can follow the setup instructions given you can get rolling fairly quickly with this simple framework.
The docs are relativley easy to follow and is a good deal of ideas flowing in place like stackoverflow. Oh and there is the <a href="http://jquerymobile.com/themeroller/" target="_blank">provided theme roller</a>
to really help get things moving.
</p>




<h2>Reason not to go there</h2>


<p><strong>Your a control freak:</strong> ok maybe a little strong :)</p>


<p>Using the JQuery Mobile framework things can begin to all look a bit the same, and if you what fine control over the look of your app you would be better served
looking else where rather than fight  with it.</p>




<h2>Projects I found useful</h2>




<h3>Icons</h3>


<p><strong></strong><a href="http://fortawesome.github.com/Font-Awesome" target="_blank">Fontawsome</a></p>




<h3>Image Gallery</h3>


<p><strong></strong><a href="www.photoswipe.com" target="_blank">Photoswipe</a></p>


<h3>Maps</h3>


<p><strong></strong><a href="http://code.google.com/p/jquery-ui-map/" target="_blank">jquery-ui-map</a></p>




<h3>Making it native</h3>


<p><a href="http://phonegap.com/" target="_blank">PhoneGap</a></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[3 Important choices when creating your App]]></title>
    <link href="http://b-spoked.com/blog/2012/08/09/3-important-choices-when-creating-your-app/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-09T21:59:00+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://b-spoked.com/blog/2012/08/09/3-important-choices-when-creating-your-app</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are considering building aor having an app created for you here are a couple of pointers of what you should think about before getting stuck in.</p>


<!-- more -->


<p>I have been dealing with a client recently that started their app project with great gusto and a 'it needs to be built yesterday'
attitude that is very common. I was to build the UI for them using thier existing app as a base - now that we have gone passed thier imposed deadline of having the app 'done'.
I gave them a call to see how it was all going - well it seemed to be comming un-stuck at the seams as they batteled to understand what they are building.</p>


<p>So what questions should they have thought while they built thier app?</p>




<h3>Who is your app for?<h3>
<p>An obvious question but the answer can often be tainted by what you believe people want or should want from you app.</p>
<p>In the instance above the app was to be built with a friendly user interface to access environmental monitoring data.
True to form the first customer just wanted access to the raw data, but this is not to say in the future other clients will
want that fancy user interface.</p>
<p></p>

<h3>What platforms will you target?</h3>
<p>Obvioulsy this will be somewhat answered when you know who your creating your app for. These days you will often
see apps created for both the iPhone and Andriod - but who are your users. In one instance it turned out that while
many of the clients aspired to own an iPhone the phones thier work provided were in-fact Blackberries.</p>

<h3>Will it continue?</h3>
<p>Is this a one-off app that will be put out but you don't intend to upgrade or extends over time?</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Is The Big Deal About Apps]]></title>
    <link href="http://b-spoked.com/blog/2012/08/04/what-is-the-big-deal-about-apps/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-04T22:58:00+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://b-spoked.com/blog/2012/08/04/what-is-the-big-deal-about-apps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the last few years there has been ever increasing talk about phone apps, especially with the iPhone app store, and it seems they are often talked about in
almost mythical terms - like an app is going to create world peace or solve world hunger.</p>


<!-- more -->


<p>My parents, probably along with many in their generation, have recently entered the world of smart phones and apps with gusto. Its cool to watch them get excited over all of these apps
and install them, get frustrated, keep the gems they find and uninstall the others (OK so I try and make sure they get rid of the ones they don't use :)).</p>


<p><strong>So what is the big deal then?</strong> well to me the big deal is the <strong>convenience</strong> - your phone is never to far from you and therefore neither are apps that you have installed on it.
Being able to track your run or ride and look at it afterward, or do a bit of reading while you are delayed or check details of an event with out having to carry a bunch of paper with you. Now that is a big deal in my books - convenience on your terms.</p>


<p>Now what about all those gimmicky apps you install and then feel dirty afterward? Well in the coming years <strong>as the pure novelty of apps wears off you will see a much higher quality and consistency of app</strong> in regards to both use and content. Because more and more the same will happen with apps as did with the web -  remember when
there was a glut of those websites with flashing titles and buttons all over the show? </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Types Of Phone Apps Are There]]></title>
    <link href="http://b-spoked.com/blog/2012/08/02/ways-to-create-phone-apps/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-02T20:16:00+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://b-spoked.com/blog/2012/08/02/ways-to-create-phone-apps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When you think about having an app developed there are options about how the app can be developed that can be worth considering before you jump in.</p>


<p>Having created apps both ways listed below there are definitely benefits to each. For me personally my preference is web apps because I can more easily
control the development and updating of the application - but in saying that there are many applications that are not suited to the web application approach.</p>


<!-- more -->


<h3>Native Apps</h3>


<p>Native apps are were you create the app using the devices native development language which differ on the iPhone, Android and other devices.</p>


<ul>
<li>Use full complement of native functions such as camera, accelerometer, address book ...</li>
<li>You can use storage on the phone for any photos/files.</li>
<li>The app will run faster.</li>
<li>App store approval process can hinder - while it helps monitor the quality it also can causes big headaches when rapidly developing new functionality.</li>
</ul>




<h3>Web Apps</h3>


<p>With web technologies getting far richer there aren't many things that you can't do these days.</p>


<ul>
<li>Create the app once for all platforms - you are targeting the phones browser so you can get greater coverage with one version of your app.</li>
<li>Quicker and easier to update - you can very quickly publish changes and fixes to your app as they aren't held up by app stores.</li>
</ul>




<h3>Other options</h3>


<p>There are always other options :) With phone apps you can create a web app and then using certain tools convert it to a native app.
This can help with the issue of creating apps that work on multiple devices - solving this issue can be a blessing depending on the audience of your app and allocated budget.</p>




<p><strong>If you want to geek out here is a good video on Native vs Web apps (its very long).</strong></p>




<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/4f2Zky_YyyQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
