<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: technical, | B-Spoked]]></title>
  <link href="http://b-spoked.com/blog/categories/technical-/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://b-spoked.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-19T22:19:25+12:00</updated>
  <id>http://b-spoked.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[B-Spoked]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[JQuery Mobile App Development]]></title>
    <link href="http://b-spoked.com/blog/2012/08/11/jquery-mobile-app-development/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-11T13:18:00+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://b-spoked.com/blog/2012/08/11/jquery-mobile-app-development</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been using <a href="http://jquerymobile.com" target="_blank">JQuery Mobile</a> for about a year now so I thought I would write up my thoughts on it.
I also will include some useful add-ins I have used in conjunction to JQuery Mobile in my development travels.</p>




<!-- more -->


<h2>Reasons to go there</h2>


<p><strong>Prototypes:</strong> Great for quick prototypes.</p>


<p>Because it is so quick to get started with a JQuery Mobile project I will often use it to create quick prototypes around a concept I am working on.
While the final product may end out being created with a different technology if you need to quickly get something running to help visualize an idea then
JQuery Mobile will defiantly be your friend.</p>




<p><strong>Ease of learning:</strong> Easy to get started and understand.</p>


<p>As long as you know a bit of simple html and can follow the setup instructions given you can get rolling fairly quickly with this simple framework.
The docs are relatively easy to follow and is a good deal of ideas flowing in place like stackoverflow. Oh and there is the <a href="http://jquerymobile.com/themeroller/" target="_blank">provided theme roller</a>
to really help get things moving.
</p>




<h2>Reasons not to go there</h2>


<p><strong>Your a control freak:</strong> ok maybe a little strong :)</p>


<p>Using the JQuery Mobile framework things can begin to all look a bit the same, and if you what fine control over the look of your app you would be better served
looking else where rather than fight  with it.</p>




<p><strong>You want full interaction with the phone:</strong></p>


<p>This obviously goes for all web apps but there comes a point where if you want to do certain things with the users phone you need to either
move to a native app for the target phones or use a technology such as PhoneGap that will convert your web app to a native app.</p>




<h2>Projects I found useful</h2>




<h3>Icons</h3>


<p><strong></strong><a href="http://fortawesome.github.com/Font-Awesome" target="_blank">Fontawsome</a></p>


<p>Great looking simple icons that you can integrate with your web app.</p>




<h3>Image Gallery</h3>


<p><strong></strong><a href="www.photoswipe.com" target="_blank">Photoswipe</a></p>


<p>A simple great looking web app enabled photo gallery</p>




<h3>Maps</h3>


<p><strong></strong><a href="http://code.google.com/p/jquery-ui-map/" target="_blank">jquery-ui-map</a></p>


<p>A full api that allows you to easily integrate mapping features into your web app.</a>

<h3>Making it native</h3>
<p><a href="http://phonegap.com/" target="_blank">PhoneGap</a></p>
<p>If you reach the point you need to go native (phone apps of course) then PhoneGap can be a great way to go.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
