<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[B-Spoked]]></title>
  <link href="http://b-spoked.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://b-spoked.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-03T00:54:00+12:00</updated>
  <id>http://b-spoked.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[B-Spoked]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[App or Crap]]></title>
    <link href="http://b-spoked.com/blog/2012/08/02/app-or-crap/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-02T23:45:00+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://b-spoked.com/blog/2012/08/02/app-or-crap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Come on app developers - just because you can doesn&#8217;t mean that you should.<p>
<p>I was having a good discussion with some of the people I do some work with at
a local design agency and we were talking about the huge number of applications that are available to us. We then started listing off some of the absolute clangers
we had installed on our phone - and then promptly un-installed.</p>
<p>While it is great to see the explosion in the area of app development so many of them are reeking of rip-off or &#8216;i wonder if i can turn a quick dollar&#8217; type apps.
So come on people - have some pride and don&#8217;t create crap.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ways To Create Phone Apps]]></title>
    <link href="http://b-spoked.com/blog/2012/08/02/ways-to-create-phone-apps/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-02T20:16:00+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://b-spoked.com/blog/2012/08/02/ways-to-create-phone-apps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When you think about having an app developed there are options about how the app can be developed that can be worth considering before you jump in.</p>


<p>Having created apps both ways listed below there are definitely benefits to each. For me personally my preference is web apps because I can more easily
control the development and updating of the application - but in saying that there are many applications that are not suited to the web application approach.</p>




<h3>Native Apps</h3>


<p>Native apps are were you create the app using the devices native development language which differ on the iPhone, Android and other devices.</p>


<ul>
<li>Use full complement of native functions such as camera, accelerometer, address book &#8230;</li>
<li>You can use storage on the phone for any photos/files.</li>
<li>The app will run faster.</li>
<li>App store approval process can hinder - while it helps monitor the quality it also can causes big headaches when rapidly developing new functionality.</li>
</ul>




<h3>Web Apps</h3>


<p>With web technologies getting far richer there aren&#8217;t many things that you can&#8217;t do these days.</p>


<ul>
<li>Create the app once for all platforms - you are targeting the phones browser so you can get greater coverage with one version of your app.</li>
<li>Quicker and easier to update - you can very quickly publish changes and fixes to your app as they aren&#8217;t held up by app stores.</li>
</ul>




<h3>Other options</h3>


<p>There are always other options :) With phone apps you can create a web app and then using certain tools convert it to a native app.
This can help with the issue of creating apps that work on multiple devices - solving this issue can be a blessing depending on the audience of your app and allocated budget.</p>




<p><strong>If you want to geek out here is a good video on Native vs Web apps (its very long).</strong></p>




<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/4f2Zky_YyyQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Love]]></title>
    <link href="http://b-spoked.com/blog/2012/08/01/i-love/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-01T22:41:00+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://b-spoked.com/blog/2012/08/01/i-love</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>My Wife</strong> - she keeps me on an even keel and is beautiful. What more could you ask for? She does insist that the dirty old pirate Johnny Depp is actually who she planned to marry :)<p>
<p><strong>My Kids</strong> - crazy and fun - crazy fun maybe :)<p>
<p><strong>My Mates</strong> - they get me out on my bike and together we are like a gang of kids again. Skids and wheelies are still cool.<p>
<p><strong>My Peers</strong> - coders / hackers / engineers - what ever you call them they are an awsome bunch really. A very giving group that achieve amazing things and more often than not let others benefit for free. Keep up the good work!<p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
