<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: thoughts | B-Spoked]]></title>
  <link href="http://b-spoked.com/blog/categories/thoughts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://b-spoked.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-14T21:57:47+12:00</updated>
  <id>http://b-spoked.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[B-Spoked]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[App or Crap]]></title>
    <link href="http://b-spoked.com/blog/2012/08/02/app-or-crap/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-02T23:45:00+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://b-spoked.com/blog/2012/08/02/app-or-crap</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Come on app developers - just because you can doesn't mean that you should.<p>
<!-- more -->
<p>I was having a good discussion with some of the people I do some work with at
a local design agency and we were talking about the huge number of applications that are available to us. We then started listing off some of the absolute clangers
we had installed on our phone - and then promptly un-installed.</p>
<p>While it is great to see the explosion in the area of app development so many of them are reeking of rip-off or 'i wonder if i can turn a quick dollar' type apps.
So come on people - have some pride and don't create crap.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Love]]></title>
    <link href="http://b-spoked.com/blog/2012/08/01/i-love/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-01T22:41:00+12:00</updated>
    <id>http://b-spoked.com/blog/2012/08/01/i-love</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>My Wife</strong> - she keeps me on an even keel and is beautiful. What more could you ask for? She does insist that the dirty old pirate Johnny Depp is actually who she planned to marry :)<p>
<p><strong>My Kids</strong> - crazy and fun - crazy fun maybe :)<p>
<p><strong>My Mates</strong> - they get me out on my bike and together we are like a gang of kids again. Skids and wheelies are still cool.<p>
<p><strong>My Peers</strong> - coders / hackers / engineers - what ever you call them they are an awsome bunch really. A very giving group that achieve amazing things and more often than not let others benefit for free. Keep up the good work!<p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
